Finding Aid for the Kagiwada Brothers Papers, 1919-1947 LSC.2010.24
UCLA Library Special Collections
Kagiwada Brothers papers
1919-1947
UCLA Library Special Collections
Kagiwada Brothers
LSC.2010.24
1 oversize_boxes
Eiho and Yoshifusa Kagiwada were brothers, born in the Kanagawa Prefecture of Japan. They emigrated to the United States where Eiho obtained a BS at Southwestern University and Yoshifusa obtained a BS from the University of Southern California. They subsequently became agents for Sun Life Assurance Company of Canada and partners in the Kagiwada Insurance Agency. This collection consists of business records and office files related to the work of the Kagiwada brothers.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942332343606533
Biography
Eiho Kagiwada was born 1895; a native of Kanagawa Prefecture, he arrived in the United States in 1914; BS, Southwestern University (1927); agent for Sun Life Assurance Co. of Canada; partner with his brother Yoshifusa in the Kagiwada Insurance Agency; he was also known as Frank E. Kagiwada.
Yoshifusa Kagiwada arrived in the United States in 1916; BS, University of Southern California (1929); was a partner with his brother Eiho and an agent for the Sun Life Assurance Co. of Canada; he was also known as Harry Y. Kagiwada.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of business records and office files related to the work of the Kagiwada brothers. The majority of the collection is made up of alphabetical office files of Canada Sun life insurance policyholders handled by the Kagiwada Insurance Agency (1924-41). The collection also includes income tax records and business records and correspondence.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Income tax records, and business correspondence and records, 1924-47 (Box 92).
Alphabetical office files of Canada Sun life insurance policyholders handled by the Kagiwada Insurance Agency, 1924-41 (Boxes 93-102).
Miscellaneous business records, 1926-42 (Boxes 103 & 720).
Related Material
Japanese American Research Project Collection of Material about Japanese in the United States (Collection 2010). Available at the UCLA Library Special Collections.
Japanese Americans -- United States -- Archives.; Business records.; Insurance agents -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Kagiwada, Yoshifusa--Archives.; Kagiwada brothers--Archives.; Kagiwada, Eiho--Archives.; Japanese American Research Project (University of California, Los Angeles)
- Kagiwada Brothers Papers, 1919-1947; 7 linear ft.
  - Income tax records, business correspondence and records., 1924-1947; 0.5 linear ft.
    - Copies of Kagiwada Eiho's federal income tax returns., 1924-1932; (11 items) (Box 92, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents note
      Also, receipts for County and school tax, County of Los Angeles, 1924-1934.
    - Copies of Kagiwada Yoshifusa's federal income tax returns., 1935, 1938 & 1947; (4 items) (Box 92, Folder 2)
      Also, California individual income tax return, 1947.
    - Business correspondence of the Kagiwada Insurance Agency., May 1926-April 1942; (156 items) (Box 92, Folder 3)
      re Canada Sun Life Insurance policies.
    - Office records of the deceased policyholders of Canada Sun Life Insurance and their death claims., 1929-1941; (approximately 150 items) (Box 92, Folder 4)
      17 cases.
    - Correspondence and office records on lapsed or cancelled Canada Sun life insurance policies., 1928-1942; (168 items) (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - Copies of application forms forwarded to the home office., 1933-1940; (12 items) (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - Lists of prospective clients., 1938-1939; (14 pieces) (Box 92, Folder 7)
  - Alphabetical office files of Canada Sun Life Insurance policyholders handled by the Kagiwada Insurance Agency., 1924-1941; 5 linear ft. (approximately 500 file folders)
    - Records on 37 policyholders, A-HA., (37 folders) (Box 93)
    - Records on 51 policyholders, HAR-INA., (51 folders) (Box 94)
    - Records on 55 policyholders, INA-KE., (55 folders) (Box 95)
    - Records on 42 policyholders, KI-KY., (42 folders) (Box 96)
    - Records on 44 policyholders, MA-MU., (44 folders) (Box 97)
    - Records on 49 policyholders, NA-NO., (49 folders) (Box 98)
    - Records on 59 policyholders, O-SA., (59 folders) (Box 99)
    - Records on 54 policyholders, SA-SU., (54 folders) (Box 100)
    - Records on 46 policyholders, SU-TSU., (46 folders) (Box 101)
    - Records on 53 policyholders, U-Z., (53 folders) (Box 102)
  - Miscellaneous Business Records, 1926-1942; 1.5 linear ft.
    - A book of cancelled checks, Kagiwada Insurance Agency., May 1933-January 1935; (1 book) (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous financial and business records, Kagiwada Insurance agency., 1919-1942; (11 items) (Box 103, Folder 2)
    - Kagiwada Yoshifusa's automobile insurance policies., 1939-1940 & 1941-1942; (2 items) (Box 103, Folder 3)
    - Profit and Loss Statements, Olympic Hotel., 1926-1930; (6 items) (Box 103, Folder 4)
    - Financial records on the Western Avenue Park Nursery., 1939-1940; (5 items) (Box 103, Folder 5)
    - Copies of federal income tax returns completed by the Kagiwada brothers for their clients., 1936-1947; (24 items) (Box 103, Folder 6)
    - Copies of applications for re-entry permits, United States Immigration and Naturalization Service, prepared by the Kagiwada brothers for clients., 1935; (9 pieces) (Box 103, Folder 7)
    - Copies of the Alien Property Reports, TFR-330, United States Treasury Department, prepared by the Kagiwadas for their clients., 1942; (44 reports) (Box 103, Folder 8)
    - Records on the late Abiko Kyutaro's Memorial Fund drive, handled by the Kagiwadas., 1937; (2 items) (Box 103, Folder 9)
    - An account book of the Kagiwada Insurance Agency., May 1926-December 1941; (1 book) (Box 720)